Bang-dah
Okay, another video shows the main straight rows in the history to style
This is a bit longer than that
It's important to have a transcendent network straight and in the history
The distances gradually extend and the first real trade routes appear
One of the earliest known routes is called the Incess Road
From around 1800 BC
Navigators begin to travel along the coast between the Indian subcontinent where spices such as black pepper and cinnamon are found
And the southern part of the Arabian Peninsula where a tree that produces asus grows
Drone-airy caravans then transport these luxury products across the Indian desert to Petra
Which becomes an important commercial crossroad between Egypt and Mesopotamia
In 331 BC, Alexander the Great during his conquests found the city of Alexandria
Soon merchant ships linked the new city to the rest of the Mediterranean basin
Alexandria then becomes the Great Warehouse for trade between India and Europe
In East Turkestan, Jade is found
This precious stone is much sought after in China as it's a sign of power and wealth
No nads then engage in Jade trade with the Chinese, notably exchanging at 13
A drink much appreciated in irid environments
But further north, a confederation of nomadic tribes spreads and threatens China
In 139 BC, the Chinese Emperor Sanzh Zhang Qian has emasodered to the unknown lands in the west
There to propose an alliance to the Yuzhai against the Zhanyu
But Zhanyuan is captured by the Zhanyu
In his health prisoner for 13 years, on his return to China, he reports to the emperor all he's worth
Regarding the various peoples of Central Asia and their products
He mentions in particular on the gestic race of horses unknown in China
In order to obtain some of these horses, the emperor agrees for the first time to trade silk
Which had been further into the exporter to till that
This is the opening of the silk roach, which gradually extends to the Middle East
In the west, after the death of Cleopatra, Egypt is ensured by the Roman Republic
Which is in the midst of the Khanian Empire
Rome is now able to increase its supply of wheat from Egypt
But it covers above all goods from the Arabian peninsula
Such as pearls, spices, and especially incense
Which is used for off-road medicine
But there are many intermediaries and the instability in the region is great
To bypass the Arabian Peninsula, the Romans go up the Nile
And come to contact with the Kingdom of Opsum
Where merchants live, who master techniques of navigation on the high seas
The Romans then open a new route to India
From the coast, they import notably Safran, Perfumes, and Diamonds
The new trade route develops rapidly, initiating the decline of the cities of the Arabian Peninsula
Soon after, the Romans come to contact with the parliants who import silk from China
The Romans then extend the silk route throughout their empire
In 224, the parliens fall and are replaced by the susivites, but trade continues
The Roman Empire then moves its capital to Constantinople
Which becomes the new commercial crossroads between East and West
Hi there, did you know?
It's a perfectly made way for a government city
And a 1 million pound a year completely taxed
From year 630 onwards, Muslim conquests threaten the Byzantine and Stassinian empires
By CC Alexanderia, the Arabs cut the road between India and Constantinople
By expanding Eastward, they now fight over the territories of Central Asia with China
Which wants to make it its protectorate
In 751, the two powers clash in Tolis
The battle turns to the advantage of the Arabs who take Chinese prisoners
Who confess to them the secrets of paper and silk manufacturing
After its defeat, China turns away from landlords to concentrate on seeruts
Which are safer and have fewer intermedia areas
The country then opens its ports to foreign traders
The Arabs quickly seize this opportunity and establish themselves at the center of a vast commercial network
The Arabs produce among other things
Carbants, they mine cobalt blue and they breed horses
In China, they also supply themselves with horse-led
In Southeast Asia and India, in addition to spices, they buy precious stones
In Africa, the trade of gold, slaves and ivory is growing
Finally, in the north, the Kazaners and the Byzantine empires supply them with European
products such as birds, honey, wood and slaves
At the heart of this immense network, Arab cities in full expansion develop rapidly
In Central Asia, nomadic turkey tribes threaten the Arab cowfights
Among them, the subject Turks seize Jerusalem in 1076
Christians who go out pilgrimage to the city are secretly persecuted
In reaction, hope urban the second launches a crusade to Jerusalem
The Italian republics that mastered navigation, CA, commercial opportunity
They offer to supply the Christians in the Near East
Where they attain commercial privileges in each of the conquered cities
In 1204, the Republic of Venice diverts the fourth crusade towards Constantinople
Which is besieged and then pillaged
The Byzantine empires dismantled, which allows the Italian republics to take over the trade
Be prune east and west all around the Mediterranean basin
In the north of Europe, several trading cities join together to develop a trade route
Between the Baltic and the North Sea
You've got exports first, rega, producers grain
While Scandinavia exports herring
In the North Sea, textile producers spring up in Flanders and England
In 1453, the Turks seize Constantinople
De-stabilizing the trade routes between Asia and Europe
Portugal takes advantage of the creation of the caravale
A large ship capable of tackling the oceans to begin explorations and an attempt to open new maritime trade routes
Along the African coasts, the Portuguese establish trading posts
And take over the slave and gold trades
The objective is now to bypass Africa to reach the Andes
The Spanish monarchy also aims at the Andes
But tries its luck with westward exploration
Thus discovering America
Portugal finally reaches the port of Calcutta and discovers a large commercial network
A man-look fleet is then charged with chasing away the new competitors
But the Portuguese prevail and quickly take control of key cross-boys
Gaining a monopoly on trade in the Indian Ocean
By bringing Asian goods directly to Europe via Africa and without intermediaries
Portugal becomes rich very quickly
At the expense of the powers that control the passage via the Middle East
To avoid competition around a newly discovered territories
Spain and Portugal agree in 1494 to draw the tortoiseous meridian
The territories to the east can be claimed by Portugal
Those to the west by Spain
In America, the Spanish conquistadors discover products unknown in the ancient world
Such as tomatoes, tobacco and potatoes
But in Europe at first, it's mainly the discovery of chocolate that interests them
The Cocoa trade develops as well as imports of precious medicine pearls
Which are the result of the conquest
But Spain still aims to reach the Andes from the west
Finally, Ferdinand Magellan succeeds in bypassing America
And after his death, his crew reaches the mollacas
Where nutmeg and cloves grow
But the Portuguese are already present in the region
And after conflicts, the two countries establish a new division line
But Spain colonizes the Philippines anyway
In order to develop trade there, the Spaniards have to avoid the Portuguese territories
And they head back to the Pacific
But the sea currents push them back
In 1565, the return route is finally found further north
It makes it possible to link Manila with Ocapolgo
In America, the Spaniards discover silver mines
Which are then intensively exploited using natives as labor
The precious metal is loaded into galleons in Caillão
Which lead for Ocapolgo and Manila
In the Philippines, Chinese merchants exchange the silver for spices
Tea, silk and porcelain which are then brought back to Ocapolgo
The silver and Chinese products are then transported to Veracruz
From where Convoys leave Regulio for Seville
While the Iberian Peninsula is rapidly becoming richer
The Dutch, the English and the French attempt in turn to seize trade routes
They found trade posts along the African coast and in the Indian Ocean
They then conquered territories, notably the Caribbean islands
Where they developed huge sugarcane plantations
Which required a large workforce
In Western Europe, slave traders leave with crockery, weapons and tools that they exchange in the Gulf of Guinea for slaves
The slaves are then transported under extremely poor conditions to the Americas
As sold to sugarcane and coffee plantations
As well as to mines such as diamond mines in Brazil
The ships then returned to Europe loaded with sugar
To back up, rum and precious stones
This trade becomes very profitable attracting new investors
Over a 200 year period between 7 and 20 million Africans
Depending on estimates are transported to America
During the 19th century, the abolition of slavery gradually puts an end to this
trying your trade
In Great Britain and industrial revolution begins
Thanks largely to the development of the coal-fired steam-matchet
With the mechanization of the weaving loan, craftsmen become workers and the textile industry bums
As a result, the demand for cotton jumped
Until then, it came mainly from India
Now, huge plantations are developed in the Caribbean and in the Southern United States
The United Kingdom produces a great deal of textiles at a reasonable price
And is looking for new markets to sell its goods
At the same time, iron and steel techniques are perfected
In the country, becomes the largest exporter of iron in the world
Iron and the steam engine revolutionized transportation
The first railroad line leaks the textile factories of Manchester to the port of Liverpool
Where shipments of American and Indian raw cotton arrive
On the seas, steamships gradually begin replacing sailing ships
The United Kingdom's strengthens its maritime domination
Seizes many territories
It develops a powerful colonial and commercial network
The batteries, the perfect workflow, doesn't exist
The good news is you can make yourself a money dot pop
Let us show you how I use my dot pop to create a team
In 1854, France intends permission from Egypt to build a canal linking the Mediterranean to the Red Sea
Such a canal had already been built in ancient times by the Ferrells
But had disappeared by the 8th century
In 1869, the Suisse canal is inaugurated
It makes it possible to travel the route to India in 60 days on a steamship
Compared to six months with a sailing ship via Africa
However, the European powers do not turn away from the African continent
After expeditions in went, European countries meet in Berlin
To divvy up Africa and regulate colonization
The peoples of Africa are subject to it and their resources plundered
In the south, large reserves of gold and diamonds are discovered
In central Africa, ivory is exploited
In addition, huge plantations are developed
Notably for rubber, necessary for the manufacturer of roots
And tires for the developing automobile industry
Plantations also appear for coffee, cocoa, tobacco
In other products that are intended for the European and American markets
In America, the United States extends its influence
In 1904, they buy from the French, the abandoned construction site for an inter-oceanic canal
The canal would considerably shorten the maritime route between the Pacific and Atlantic oceans
10 years later, the Panama Canal is inaugurated
With this new key passageway controlled by the United States
During World War I, new oil-powered weapons are here on land at sea and in the air
At the end of the war, the demand for oil sky-rockets
While the automobile and aviation industries developed
At that time, oil comes mainly from the United States
Mexico and the Caspian Sea
But soon, especially after World War II, huge deposits are discovered in the Middle East and America
This strategic resource becomes abundant and cheap and all trade intensifies
The aviation boom makes it possible to trade across the world via the air
This is the beginning of globalization
That is, the acceleration of trade on worldwide scale
But the situation in the Middle East and Africa is increasingly unstable
In 1967, the Six-Day War takes place
Israel occupies the Sinai up to the banks of the Suez Canal
Which is then closed for eight years, forcing ships to bypass Africa
In addition, in the 1970s, two oil shocks caused the price of oil to increase dramatically
Countries that depend on this so-called black gold
Without producing it, turn to other types of energy, including nuclear power
Uranium becomes a very popular resource
Mainly extracted from mines in Canada and the Congo
New deposits are quickly exploited all over the world
In the 1980s and 1980s, the United States sees a boom
And a relatively new and very promising sector
Electronics and computer technologies
Apple launches their first personal computer and its intermediate success
Japan quickly follows the USA
Beginning a period of desolate technological development
In its automobile and electronics industries
Several countries in the Far East are inspired by Japan
And specialize in the export of electronic components
Rare earth metals needed in the manufacture of electronics
Become a strategic raw material
Well the vast majority of the deposits are discovered in China
In 2001, China becomes a member of the World Trade Organization
The country attracts foreign companies thanks to its cheap labor force
At the same time, advantages are granted to foreign investors
And export quotas are abolished
Soon, textiles made in China, flood American and European markets
Many companies relocate their factories to China
The country gradually becomes the world's factory
With its economy experiencing explosive growth
Allowing for rapid development
To secure its economy in 2013, the country begins the creation of the new soap roads
The objective is to ensure its supply of raw materials
And also to increase its exports of manufactured products
Steel and aluminum
Throughout the world, roads, railroads and seaports are massively financed by China
With the aim of connecting the country to all continents
New initiatives are being discussed
Such as the construction of a railor line
That would link China to the United States
Through a tunnel under the barren street
Or the construction of an inter-Ocean canal in Nicaragua
While some countries are opposed to this project
China has already convinced about 140 countries to host these new silk roads
Which should be finalized by 2049
When the peoples Republic of China will celebrate its 100th anniversary
According to some estimates
The world's largest trade is in arms
Followed by the drug trade
With an estimated annual turnover of nearly $500 billion
This clandestine trade is controlled by criminal networks
Opium poppy saw produced in Asia
In the Golden Triangle and the Golden Crescent
Cannabis resin is mainly produced in Morocco
In cocaine comes mainly from Colombia
The drugs are transported by different rules
To Europe and the United States
Which are the biggest consumers
Today the main maritime trade route circles below
Passing through strategic streets and channels
It passes through North America
The Panama Canal
Europe
The Mediterranean
The Suez Canal
The Indian Ocean
And Asia
Moreover the search for new trade routes never stops
At the North Pole
The melting of the ice caused by climate change
Makes it possible to envisage the opening of new maritime routes
That are short and therefore less costly in terms of fuel
While also avoiding taxes
Living when having to pass through the Suez for Panama canals
These new routes could benefit Russia and Canada in particular
The major powers well understand the stakes at play
In these potential future routes
The United States and the European Union
Are demanding free navigation
While China intends to develop a polar so corroded
If China dollar makes use of the ship
What is the main demand for US-level solar naval fishing targets
And what is the CCP's largestそうですね model
Because only Chinese can implement European technologies
Since expectancy is only told
Then theres the ship will be in poor Temperature
in case tree and what happened to die and then before we go with the discussion
of the globalization means them. I like to talk something about the classes
right so all the slides you will be here, all main slides you will be here
and the materials here, so it goes the slides and then we will have a textbook
and we sometimes will follow the textbook that this one can be downloaded
here there's an introduction to internet economics there's new perspective
on the global economy so given down this one and there are four
assessments of this course here
assessments
yeah this will include the assessment of course including the assignments
and there will be some team works and also checkings and some others so okay
so all the best but yeah there's three parts of this so we have several assignments
and also team works here so three parts of this and another one will be
got another one with offline this will be some interaction or your performance
in the class and the after class okay so there'll be a 10% will be
say there's there's going to be controlled or there to be say there's to be
controlled by by the professors teachers that gets 10% of offline okay so and sometimes
let me go some of the the materials or sometimes we will give some some readings but not a week
by week so there's got some some readings but but this is not important if I assign some readings
if I assign some reading I will put them under this folder okay and this one this one is not
important this one is not too important
so we'll continue to discuss the globalization
so what's the situation of the current globalization something like this
as we know from the other second world then again here we've got a different terms for globalization
one of them a difference maybe that I do the generalization two in the three rights
after we'll want to see here shows the choice important exports as a percentage of GDP in the world
increase from 15% to about 17 18% then this maybe that's the eighties okay that's the eighties
85 86 86 here increase to 2008 about two Sundays this is about close to 30% and then it's
very slowly like this so we got a three terms here for globalization after second world the first
one in globalization second hyper globalization and now we're in the purge of the
globalization that means now we are moving fast love like this snow the
why so there's some people say that the globalization now is the peak and then we move down from the peak
because as we just see here now this is a peak and then go down here right
got them but we see also see the slope now from positive slope to a bit negative slope here
and then but then this is not the real case as we see of the details if you say there's the peak
globalization that means they asked all right the highest of the
traits as question of GDP so people say that the globalization now is stopped or this is
globalization or this they are declining that decalbellization we're not connecting with one another
now so and then here we choose will be some forces is not
two right so because even if we see this very similar to what we just mentioned then 19% to 29%
and then 50% and all that but this is to be import exporter of GDP but it's another version of
the peak globalization but this is quite different if we look at this what if we look at this
because from 2-390 to 2020 the increase from 50% to 42% if we take this look in details
as we just mentioned the status here writes the from 60 to 90s this increase and then from around 90
the trading booth starts growing much faster at the 2-390s because of global financial crisis
and also the trading shocks so people refer to this a great trade complex
claps in the world so globalization is now decalbellization of
globalization or even desta and declining globalization but which does the same mean mistakes
because what we see just now is an overall situation in the world if we look the
individual countries with them China United States and Japan you're in union and some others
so it's the China all right they picked in 2008 instead of 2006 instead of 2008 and then
you're not a star it's then this you know states the black one 2011 and then Japan 2014
and you'll see European Union still moving out a bit so it's not big and this one decreased
to become this is the very special periods because of financial crisis so we cannot say this is
a for China actually this is because after financial crisis it decreased further but then for the
other three economies of financial crisis increased so it was the they are not picked
and here also shows that this economy made the economy
as trades as percentage of GDP from 70s to 2020 then these are even stated that they are
increasing but we see they are increasing right they're increasing so not picked they're not
big and the larger trading goods is the traders if European Union has the single economy
account for 30% China only 12% United States 11% then if we look at more countries the vertical
axis shows this one being the peak percentage changed between the the axis is the
percentage change of the trades in percentage of GDP rise there's a vertical from
2020 is a vertical one vertical check there's a difference between 2020 and 2009 and then
digital axis has to be the different between 2009 and 1990 and this is the this is a purist that's
done that faster growth period and this purist is a slow growth of globalization slow growth
so if we see the difference between them and if we see that which could be the difference
in the slow growth period right if the growth rate of percentage is higher in the second
period then in the first period then they will be in the upper panel here as a more than 0%
right this is if it's higher than 2020 then 2008 if the percentage is higher in 2008 then 1990
they must be to the right because this will be positive so from this you can see here if this
country in both periods are negative that means 2008 is higher than 1990 and 2020 is higher than
2008 so they must be here you both a growth slow so all these countries might be peakers that means
it's percentage of trades in the GDP have decreasing or risk of highest and now decreasing including
front front document the Germany adds Australia and Sweden dependent damal
they are if they are over there then these are non-peekers okay it's that they're the
non-peekers so all of these are not not people they're still increasing like each one
you're in yielding and then maybe the national now the national national national
as well as them you get problems they're increasing so all other countries see not all the countries
start the peakers that is they're still in their percentage of trading GDP has still increasing
and also you can see here China's engaging to the world global change from 1995 to 2018
we are selling more in intermediate products to the world and finally
last sometimes maybe last or maybe similar roughly the same 1% about last 1% of the
intermediate from the world but it was more than 2% close to 3% of intermediate exports to the world
so why the trade goods ratio decrease overall the trade ratio decrease as a percentage of GDP
to the trade 20 GDP decrease then there must be some some things a lot but then if we look
they're trading a decreasing we need to look at the water this trade of water and trade of values
right if they're they're not decreasing that what the important role of the
commensurate crisis crisis or suit cycles so this is the difference so if we look at this
into decomposing to details we'll see here the lots of world rich GDP and real exports actually
they're increasing for GDP the lots of increasing and then for export also increasing apart
their difference are the difference their access here this will be the last scale since they're
exports and also the so we'll see here the real GDP we're export to real GDP ratio now from
if we take the two-centre 15 and as 100 then we'll see now two some nights is one is three and two
are 2021 99% where close to each other so they're not really decreasing because right but a bit
a very small decrease for that then when we trade with other countries right so we see here
as decreasing the total goods export and decreasing but if we decompose into three categories
three industries there's agricultural products there's the raw material the mining fields and that
actions most in not all of this are decreasing but for agriculture a bit increase and for the
agriculture is increasing and only for this one and decrease but money and decreasing and we see
the manufacturing by the staff as we see here for agriculture are increasing for goods
the different goods are increasing only the mine and few mining field products are decreasing
from 2020 so the general the aggregate the aggregate decreasing is due to the raw material
actually see here right this is very clear the prices when we talk about trade we're talking about
the their values and the value is a is a quantitative times the price and the price will fuse
and the mining that decreasing so even if we trade the same content you would trade the same
but it's pricey decreasing then the value is decreasing stay there's a fuse and mine but for
agriculture products and manufacturing products they're not decreasing they're fast but this is
this is the only for the fuse and mine products okay so that's if we compared the the
trillion in mine and you might lose in the fields this is the trades in values and then this
is trading values means the content so we see the quantity the traded value are increasing the
quantity increasing but why the values are decreasing because the price are decreasing so it is not because
the trade are the trade the world smaller because the price are smaller and lower than before
so the trade of value is lower than before then in this case them if we look at the values
but not the world is we'll see trades are smaller than before but if we look at the quantities
who are trading more than before so that is globalization is still growing not the decreasing right
and also supply chains the supply chains are important because the production is not
today the production is not same as the centuries ago today the production of the final product
involve the import of the raw materials import its immediate products import of
many components from different countries and the assembly of final products and the production
base indicator for the end of of sure of sure it means the much national companies
are in the United States you are in union with advanced countries nations they locate some
production activities production tasks to developing countries right so from the second
as 1970s they are doing this they are located the production activities from one country to another
but today they have already maximized a location of all activities because say in 1970 all the
activities we have three activities say that we have three activities in the raw materials
production assembled into final products all of this in 1960s up produced up performing in
the United States and then up dancing the off-shoreing some activity to other countries so this to
maybe two South East Asian countries and this remains in United States and this to some other
countries okay so starting to off-shoreing some of this production tasks to the places where
the production efficiency is highest or the cost is lowest and then from 1960s 90s to today to two
thousands now the fourth decades or three decades right they already have located the
activities to the places we should run to low cost there's no further places they can find to
locate to further locate to under-press it so for example the cost here is the cost of 50
they cannot find any place lower the cost of low their 50 no place they can find so that is
the choice between these locations from see that is the China and this maybe that's the
in China okay they already this is already the location best performed this task and this is
the location that's the performance task with high efficiency so no reason to move them from
China to other countries or from China to other locations so that is the this is what is said
the end of off-shoreing expansion of facts no expansion of such an off-shoreing they already
includes everything in their right places so folks on the show to merit right activity the job
is a bit bigger right so that's the foreign from sit to 5% to 29% in 2013 but the rules to sit
to 1% in 2018 and try to base the values of reshoring reshoring what does that mean so if the
United States are aren't going to be a performance in the United States and now some tasks they have to
to China this is this is of of short this of shorting so the activity is the movie from the United
States to China but now the the political reasons Biden or some others Obama they tried to move the
production activities from China from Mexico from Southeast Asian countries back to your states
and this is this is a reshoring this is a reshoring so share the intermediate imports and exports
there's a biggest manufacturing economy and not this engage in from supply chain if they move back
so there's not much of the trade of the of the imports of the intermediate products okay so that is the
from the countries at the same size and then we can see here we can see here share the world
manufacturing of GDP in in these countries g7 countries industrial six that's an emerging
countries in new industries countries it's share of the GP in the world for g7 countries decreased
from 60% to 38% of 37% and in the 36 moved from 10% to 35% to 38% and the rest of the world's
rapidly signed 26% to 20% and here this will be the value added as crystalized across
productions what does the value added to mean the value added means them if we produce the
the products three stages raw materials and the production of the intermediate products and in
the final product so if we put this 50 okay and then here we got maybe a certain and it got
20 so we got a final product you can find the product is it's 100 and this is a gross value
but this 20 30 and 50 is a value added okay it's about added so there isn't decreasing because
there's not much trade between the AP service or the some of the decreasing and then we will discuss
this on next time that's so much but still
all
what
but i drifted in the animation
so you don't go to fighting
when i'm fighting, i try my best
otherwise i do the action
well, now will try my single
wow
what do u do ?
lets write a speech
LC
ok
It's okay, it's okay if you go over it, boys
They're going to go over the thread
I'm going to put it on the top.
I'm going to put it on.
It's going to be nice and long.
It's going to be nice too.
To be nice and long.
That's just shorts.
I'm going to have to go back to the
next day.
I'm going to have to go back to the next
day.
I'm going to have to go back to the
next day.
I'm going to have to go back to the next
day.
I'm going to have to go back to the next day.
I'm going to have to go back to the next
day.
I'm going to have to go back to the next day.